Michael Clarke

Brooklyn, NY https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-clarke-462511134/ https://github.com/MichaelClarkeO

Brand Statement

I am a hardworker whose resilience is geared to productive results. These past few months I've dedicated myself and my time to becoming a software engineer and increasing my ability to think like a software engineer. I'm highly motivated to get the opportunity to learn from others as well as share the knowledge that I have gained. My ability to consistently be reliable would be an asset to any company. My personal growth is very important to me. I have gained a ton of character and humility from my previous experiences. A few of my biggest interests at the moment are traveling, gaining skills/knowledge, and networking and interacting with others.

Skills

JavascriptCSSMONGODBPythonDjangoPOSTGRESQLJqueryMERN STACKGITHUB

HTML REACT

Experience

Brooklyn, New York - December 2021- March 2022

General Assembly - Software Engineer Scholar

A 500-hour full-stack Software Engineer immersive program focused on the most popular front and backend programming languages, parsing documentation, collaborative projects, researching solutions and critical thinking. Throughout the program I worked on a number of individual and collaborative projects, including:

- Golf Utilized HTML5, CSS and JavaScript to develop a card game. A two player game where each player takes turns selecting 4 cards from a deck. The player with the lower sum when the game is called is the winner.
- YardSale Utilizing MEN Stack my partner and I created a used item website. A website
 geared towards selling and buying local goods. Think Offerup or Letgo. This project
 enforced our learned skills in building routes, creating RESTful API, implementing
 relationships(one-to-many/ many-to-many), and using Bulma CSS framework.
- Spacefarer Using Django and Python my group created a traveler website for our solar system. Navigating through Django's built in methods, creating paths for each webpage, authenticating admin/user logins, and applying bootstrap's open source toolkit to make our website presentable.

Brooklyn, New York - August 2021 - PRESENT

Henry Norman Hotel - Front Desk/ Night Audit

- To set a high standard for all incoming guests.
- Following all COVID protocols to ensure the safety and comfort of our guests.

- Having the capability to work alone as well as part of a collaborative team to reach our goals.
- Representing Henry Norman Hotel in a professional manner at all times.

Brooklyn, New York - December 2018 - January 2020

AT&T - Assistant Manager

- Display excellent communication and interpersonal skills to all customers.
- Handle all customer complaints and difficult situations using problem solving techniques.
- Mastered ability to make sales and create an enjoyable transaction experience for each customer.

Orlando, Florida - April 2016 - June 2018

Quality Inn - Front Desk Manager

- Operating, advising and coordinating all guest service requests.
- Creating work schedules and logging hours for all employees.
- Providing friendly reception to all guests.

Education

Florida Agricultural and Mechanical University - Architecture, 2010-2013 General Assembly - Software Engineering Graduate, 2022